Frederic Freilicher Papers /3024
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frederic Freilicher Papers
1963-1973
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Freilicher, Frederic
/3024
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
State University of New York (SUNY) Faculty Senate minutes, as well as arbitration papers.
3073825
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 12, 2016
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, October 11, 2022
Biographical / Historical
Frederic Freilicher is a labor and employment attorney who taught as an Assistant Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations in the 1960s and 1970s.
After graduating from Harvard University (BA, 1960) and Columbia Law School (JD, 1963), Freilicher worked at the National Labor Relations Board (1963-1967), then joined the faculty of Cornell University. After leaving Cornell in 1973, Frelicher worked in government service, first in the Department of Justice's Civil Rights Division and Antitrust Division, and later with the National Labor Relations Board. Freilicher is an attorney at Hunton & Williams LLP.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1945 as the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, the ILR School today is advancing the world of work through teaching, research and outreach. ILR's mission is to prepare leaders, inform national and international employment and labor policy, and improve working lives, but as the world of work evolves, the school's focus broadens to keep pace with that change.
ILR studies many areas that shape the working world and contribute to an organization's success in a global economy. These include human resource management; labor-management relations; labor economics; organizational behavior; international and comparative labor; labor relations, labor law and history; conflict resolution; management development; diversity management; employment and disability; and social statistics.
An ILR education is grounded in the social sciences. Students and faculty explore and gain an understanding of human behavior through the lens of the workplace. Students also learn how organizations work and how they fit into the larger society and economy. As a result, they acquire knowledge and skills that help them to solve problems on-the-job and to build and manage productive work relationships. An ILR education, for students and professionals, is practical and applied.
ILR has more full-time faculty involved in teaching and research that spans the broad range of work and employment disciplines than any other educational institution of its kind. Its Martin P. Catherwood Library is regarded as the most comprehensive source of information in North America on work, employment and labor issues.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6047: Archives Information File
Labor laws and legislation -- United States -- Cases; Freilicher, Frederic.; United States. National Labor Relations Board
3073825
- United States Court of Appeals - First Circuit (Box 1, Folder 1)
- United States Court of Appeals - Second Circuit (Box 1, Folder 2)
- United States Court of Appeals - Third Circuit (Box 1, Folder 3)
- United States Court of Appeals - Fourth Circuit (Box 1, Folder 4)
- United States Court of Appeals - Fifth Circuit (Box 1, Folder 5)
- United States Court of Appeals - Sixth Circuit (Box 1, Folder 6)
- United States Court of Appeals - Seventh Circuit (Box 2, Folder 1)
- United States Court of Appeals - Eight Circuit (Box 2, Folder 2)
- United States Court of Appeals - Ninth Circuit (Box 2, Folder 3)
- United States Court of Appeals - Tenth Circuit (Box 2, Folder 4)
- United States Court of Appeals - District of Columbia Circuit (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Supreme Court of the United States, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Releases and Addresses (Box 2, Folder 7)
- State University of New York - Master Plan of 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Faculty Senate Directory, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - Center at Binghamton (10/24-25/1969) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College of Forestry at Syracuse (5/8-9/1970) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College at Buffalo (2/5-6/1971) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College at Geneseo (5/7-8/1971) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Faculty Senate Minutes- College at Alfred (10/22-23/1971) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Final Report of ILR Planning Committee, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- State University of New York - 1972 Master Plan (Box 3, Folder 9)
- SUNY Questionnaire (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Norton Governance (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Faculty Senate Directory, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- SUNY (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - Center at Albany, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College at Potsdam, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College at Brockport, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College at Buffalo, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College of Forestry at Syracuse, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - Alfred, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - College at Brockport, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Faculty Senate Minutes - Center at Buffalo, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous SUNY (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Elmira School District and Elmira Teacher's Association (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Additional Budget Information (Fveilichev) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Stipends (Fveilichev) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- CTD Proposal (Box 4, Folder 4)
- CTD Article IV B - School Psychologists and Guidance Counselors (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Supplemental Salary (Freilicher) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Current and Past Contacts (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Binding Arbitration (Freilicher) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Board Proposal (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Classroom Teachers Division Copy: Discipline Policy, Letter to Nurses, Letter to Association (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Additional CTD Association Privileges (Freilicher) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- CTD Association Privileges (Box 4, Folder 12)
- CTD Insurance (Freilicher) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- CTD Leaves (Box 4, Folder 14)
- CTD Discipline (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Evaluation (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Elementary Preparation Time (Box 4, Folder 17)
- City of Elmira School District: Tentative Budget for 7/1/1971 - 6/30/1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- CTD Salary Proposal (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Maximum Class Loads (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Budget Information (Box 4, Folder 21)
- City of Elmira School District: Budget for 7/1/1970 - 6/30/1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Teacher Newsletter and Handbook (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Half Day Sessions (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Summary of Estimated General Fund Appropriations and Notes for 7/1/1969 - 6/30/1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- BOCES City School District - Elmira (Box 4, Folder 26)
- State of NY Public Employment Relations Boars Recommendations (Elmira School Board v. CTD) (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Public Employment Relations Board Notes (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Work to be Done (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Elmira CTD Fact-Finding (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Corning Mediation 1971 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- South Colonie Mediation (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Professor Frederick Freilicher (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Auburn Police Fact-Finding (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Auburn Advisory Arbitration (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Jamestown Police Arbitration (Box 5, Folder 3)
- WBBF Case (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Kason Hardware Arbitration (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Pennsylvania Blue Collar Unit (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Seneca Falls Arbitration (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Vestal Conciliation (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Auburn Fireman Fact-finding 70 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- City of Hackensack - Objections (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Elmira Teachers Fact-Finding (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Schuyler County Mediation (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Batavia Fact-Finding (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Binghamton Fire Fighter Fact-Finding (Box 6, Folder 8)
- DePugh Arbitration (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Webster Mediation (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Allegheny Fact-Finding (Box 7, Folder 2)
- City of Auburn Collective Bargaining (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Auburn Fact-Finding (Box 7, Folder 4)
- A&P Arbitration (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Fulton Arbitration (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Fulton Fact-Finding (Box 7, Folder 7)